
What is made up of NSError object? 
There are three parts of NSError object: a domain, an error code, and a user info dictionary. 
The domain is a string that identifies what categories of errors this error is coming from.


What Are B-Trees? 
B-trees are search trees that provide an ordered key-value store with excellent performance characteristics. In principle, each node maintains a sorted array of its own elements, and another array for its children.


What is Enum ?
Enum is a type that basically contains a group of related values in same umbrella.

What is @synthesize in Objective-C ? 
synthesize generates getter and setter methods for your property.

What is @dynamic in Objective-C ? 
We use dynamic for subclasses of NSManagedObject. @dynamic tells the compiler that getter and setters are implemented somewhere else.

Why do we use synchronized ? 
synchronized guarantees that only one thread can be executing that code in the block at any given time.

What is the difference strong, weaks, read only and copy ?

strong, weak, assign property attributes define how memory for that property will be managed.

Strong means that the reference count will be increased and
the reference to it will be maintained through the life of the object

Weak, means that we are pointing to an object but not increasing its reference count. It’s often used when creating a parent child relationship. The parent has a strong reference to the child but the child only has a weak reference to the parent.

Read only, we can set the property initially but then it can’t be changed.

Copy, means that we’re copying the value of the object when it’s created. Also prevents its value from changing.

What is Dynamic Dispatch ? 
Dynamic Dispatch is the process of selecting which implementation
of a polymorphic operation that’s a method or a function to call at run time. This means, that when we wanna invoke our methods like object method. but Swift does not default to dynamic dispatch

What’s Code Coverage ? 
Code coverage is a metric that helps us to measure the value of our unit tests.

What’s the difference between the frame and the bounds? 
The bounds of a UIView is the rectangle, expressed as a location (x,y) and size (width,height) relative to its own coordinate system (0,0). 
The frame of a UIView is the rectangle, expressed as a location (x,y) and size (width,height) relative to the superview it is contained within.

What is Responder Chain ? 
A ResponderChain is a hierarchy of objects that have the opportunity to respond to events received.

What is Regular expressions ? 
Regular expressions are special string patterns that describe how to search through a string.

What is Adapter Pattern ? 
An Adapter allows classes with incompatible interfaces to work together. It wraps itself around an object and exposes a standard interface to interact with that object.

What is Observer Pattern ? 
In the Observer pattern, one object notifies other objects of any state changes.
Cocoa implements the observer pattern in two ways: Notifications and Key-Value Observing (KVO).

Explain MVC
Models — responsible for the domain data or a data access layer which manipulates the data, think of ‘Person’ or ‘PersonDataProvider’ classes.
Views — responsible for the presentation layer (GUI), for iOS environment think of everything starting with ‘UI’ prefix.
Controller/Presenter/ViewModel — the glue or the mediator between the Model and the View, in general responsible for altering the Model by reacting to the user’s actions performed on the View and updating the View with changes from the Model.

What is JSON/PLIST limits ?
-We create your objects and then serialized them to disk..
-It’s great and very limited use cases.
-We can’t obviously use complex queries to filter your results.
-It’s very slow.
-Each time we need something, we need to either serialize or deserialize it.
-it’s not thread-safe.

What is Realm benefits ?
-An open-source database framework.
-Implemented from scratch.
-Zero copy object store.
-Fast.

 How many are there APIs for battery-efficient location tracking ? 
There are 3 apis.
-Significant location changes — the location is delivered approximately every 500 metres (usually up to 1 km)
-Region monitoring — track enter/exit events from circular regions with a radius equal to 100m or more. Region monitoring is the most precise API after GPS.
-Visit events — monitor place Visit events which are enters/exits from a place (home/office).

What is the Swift main advantage ? 
To mention some of the main advantages of Swift:

-Optional Types, which make applications crash-resistant
-Built-in error handling
-Closures
-Much faster compared to other languages
-Type-safe language
-Supports pattern matching

Explain generics in Swift ? 
Generics create code that does not get specific about underlying data types. 

Explain lazy in Swift ? 
An initial value of the lazy stored properties is calculated only when the property is called for the first time. There are situations when the lazy properties come very handy to developers.

 Explain what is defer ? 
defer keyword which provides a block of code that will be executed in the case when execution is leaving the current scope.

Why it is better to use higher order functions?
Functions that take another function as a parameter, or return a function, as a result, are known as higher-order functions. Swift defines these functions as CollectionType.
The very basic higher order function is a filter

What is Concurrency ?
Concurrency is dividing up the execution paths of your program so that they are possibly running at the same time. 

What is ARC ?

ARC is a compile time feature that is Apple’s version of automated memory management. It stands for Automatic Reference Counting. This means that it only frees up memory for objects when there are zero strong references/ to them.

What is iOS 11 SDK Features for Developers ?

New MapKit Markers
Configurable File Headers
Block Based UITableView Updates
MapKit Clustering
Closure Based KVO
Vector UIImage Support
New MapKit Display Type
Named colors in Asset Catalog
Password Autofill
Face landmarks, Barcode and Text Detection
Multitasking using the new floating Dock, slide-over apps, pinned apps, and the new App Switcher
Location Permission: A flashing blue status bar anytime an app is collecting your location data in the background. Updated locations permissions that always give the user the ability to choose only to share location while using the app.

What is the three major debugging improvements in Xcode 8 ?

The View Debugger lets us visualize our layouts and see constraint definitions at runtime. Although this has been around since Xcode 6, Xcode 8 introduces some handy new warnings for constraint conflicts and other great convenience features.
The Thread Sanitizer is an all new runtime tool in Xcode 8 that alerts you to threading issues — most notably, potential race conditions.
The Memory Graph Debugger is also brand new to Xcode 8. It provides visualization of your app’s memory graph at a point in time and flags leaks in the Issue navigator.

Please explain final keyword into the class ?

By adding the keyword final in front of the method name, we prevent the method from being overridden. If we can replace the final class keyword with a single word static and get the same behavior.

What is the difference open & public access level ?

open allows other modules to use the class and inherit the class; for members, it allows others modules to use the member and override it.

public only allows other modules to use the public classes and the public members. Public classes can no longer be subclassed, nor public members can be overridden.

What is the difference fileprivate, private and public private(set) access level ?

fileprivate is accessible within the current file, private is accessible within the current declaration.

public private(set) means getter is public, but the setter is private.

What is bitcode ?
Bitcode refers to to the type of code: “LLVM Bitcode” that is sent to iTunes Connect. This allows Apple to use certain calculations to re-optimize apps further (e.g: possibly downsize executable sizes). If Apple needs to alter your executable then they can do this without a new build being uploaded.

What problems does delegation solve?

Avoiding tight coupling of objects
Modifying behavior and appearance without the need to subclass objects
Allowing tasks to be handed off to any arbitrary object

What is the major purposes of Frameworks?
Frameworks have three major purposes:
Code encapsulation
Code modularity
Code reuse

Explain Swift Package Manager

The Swift Package Manager will help to vastly improve the Swift ecosystem, making Swift much easier to use and deploy on platforms without Xcode such as Linux. The Swift Package Manager also addresses the problem of dependency hell that can happen when using many interdependent libraries.

The Swift Package Manager only supports using the master branch. Swift Package Manager now supports packages with Swift, C, C++ and Objective-C.

 What is the difference between a delegate and an NSNotification?
Delegates and NSNotifications can be used to accomplish nearly the same functionality. However, delegates are one-to-one while NSNotifications are one-to-many.

Why do we use a delegate pattern to be notified of the text field’s events?
Because at most only a single object needs to know about the event.

How is an inout parameter different from a regular parameter?
A Inout passes by reference while a regular parameter passes by value.

Explain View Controller Lifecycle events order ?

There are a few different lifecycle event

- loadView
  Creates the view that the controller manages. It’s only called when the view controller is created and only when done programatically.
- viewDidLoad
  Called after the controller’s view is loaded into memory. It’s only called when the view is created.
- viewWillAppear

It’s called whenever the view is presented on the screen. In this step the view has bounds defined but the orientation is not applied.
- viewWillLayoutSubviews

Called to notify the view controller that its view is about to layout its subviews. This method is called every time the frame changes
- viewDidLayoutSubviews

Called to notify the view controller that its view has just laid out its subviews. Make additional changes here after the view lays out its subviews.
- viewDidAppear

Notifies the view controller that its view was added to a view hierarchy.
- viewWillDisappear

Before the transition to the next view controller happens and the origin view controller gets removed from screen, this method gets called.
- viewDidDisappear

After a view controller gets removed from the screen, this method gets called. You usually override this method to stop tasks that are should
not run while a view controller is not on screen.


What is interface?

The @interface in Objective-C has nothing to do with Java interfaces. It simply declares a public interface of a class, its public API.

What are the states of an iOS App?
Non-running — The app is not running.
Inactive — The app is running in the foreground, but not receiving events. An iOS app can be placed into an inactive state, for example, when a call or SMS message is received.
Active — The app is running in the foreground, and receiving events.
Background — The app is running in the background, and executing code.
Suspended — The app is in the background, but no code is being executed.

What are the most important application delegate methods a developer should handle ?

The operating system calls specific methods within the application delegate to facilitate transitioning to and from various states. The seven most important application delegate methods a developer should handle are:

application:willFinishLaunchingWithOptions
Method called when the launch process is initiated. This is the first opportunity to execute any code within the app.

application:didFinishLaunchingWithOptions
Method called when the launch process is nearly complete. Since this method is called is before any of the app’s windows are displayed, it is the last opportunity to prepare the interface and make any final adjustments.

applicationDidBecomeActive
Once the application has become active, the application delegate will receive a callback notification message via the method applicationDidBecomeActive.

This method is also called each time the app returns to an active state from a previous switch to inactive from a resulting phone call or SMS.

applicationWillResignActive
There are several conditions that will spawn the applicationWillResignActive method. Each time a temporary event, such as a phone call, happens this method gets called. It is also important to note that “quitting” an iOS app does not terminate the processes, but rather moves the app to the background.

applicationDidEnterBackground
This method is called when an iOS app is running, but no longer in the foreground. In other words, the user interface is not currently being displayed. According to Apple’s UIApplicationDelegate Protocol Reference, the app has approximately five seconds to perform tasks and return. If the method does not return within five seconds, the application is terminated.

applicationWillEnterForeground
This method is called as an app is preparing to move from the background to the foreground. The app, however, is not moved into an active state without the applicationDidBecomeActive method being called. This method gives a developer the opportunity to re-establish the settings of the previous running state before the app becomes active.

applicationWillTerminate
This method notifies your application delegate when a termination event has been triggered. Hitting the home button no longer quits the application. Force quitting the iOS app, or shutting down the device triggers the applicationWillTerminate method. This is the opportunity to save the application configuration, settings, and user preferences.

--
What does code signing do?
Signing our app allows iOS to identify who signed our app and to verify that our app hasn’t been modified since you signed it. The Signing Identity consists of a public-private key pair that Apple creates for us.

What is the difference between property and instance variable?
A property is a more abstract concept. An instance variable is literally just a storage slot, like a slot in a struct. Normally other objects are never supposed to access them directly. Usually a property will return or set an instance variable, but it could use data from several or none at all.

Explain difference between SDK and Framework ?
SDK is a set of software development tools. This set is used for creation of applications. Framework is basically a platform which is used for developing software applications. It provides the necessary foundation on which the programs can be developed for a specific platform. SDK and Framework complement each other, and SDKs are available for frameworks.

Explain difference between SDK and Framework ?
SDK is a set of software development tools. This set is used for creation of applications. Framework is basically a platform which is used for developing software applications. 
It provides the necessary foundation on which the programs can be developed for a specific platform. SDK and Framework complement each other, and SDKs are available for frameworks.

Why is everything in a do-catch block?

In Swift, errors are thrown and handled inside of do-catch blocks.

What is ARC and how is it different from AutoRelease?

Autorelease is still used ARC. ARC is used inside the scope, autorelease is used outside the scope of the function.


What is the relation between iVar and @property?

iVar is an instance variable. It cannot be accessed unless we create accessors, which are generated by @property. iVar and its counterpart @property can be of different names.

Why do we need to specify self to refer to a stored property or a method When writing asynchronous code?

Since the code is dispatched to a background thread we need to capture a reference to the correct object.

--

What is intrinsic content size?

Every view that contains content can calculate its intrinsic content size. The intrinsic content size is calculated by a method on every UIView instance. This method returns a CGSize instance.

--
What is Instruments?

Instrument is a powerful performance tuning tool to analyze that performance, memory footprint, smooth animation, energy usage, leaks and file/network activity.

--

What is Deep Linking?

Deep linking is a way to pass data to your application from any platform like, website or any other application. By tapping once on link, you can pass necessary data to your application.

--
Explain super keyword in child class

We use the super keyword to call the parent class initializer after setting the child class stored property.

--
Explain Polymorphism

Polymorphism is the ability of a class instance to be substituted by a class instance of one of its subclasses.
--

Explain In-app Purchase products and subscriptions

Consumable products: can be purchased more than once and used items would have to re-purchase.
Non-consumable products: user would be able to restore this functionality in the future, should they need to reinstall the app for any reason. We can also add subscriptions to our app.
Non-Renewing Subscription: Used for a certain amount of time and certain content.
Auto-Renewing Subscription: Used for recurring monthly subscriptions.

--

26- What is HealthKit ?

HealthKit is a framework on iOS. It stores health and fitness data in a central location. It takes in data from multiple sources, which could be different devices. It allows users to control access to their data and maintains privacy of user data. Data is synced between your phone and your watch.

--
Explain Neural networks with Core ML

Neural networks and deep learning currently provide the best solutions to many problems in image recognition, speech recognition, and natural language processing.

Core ML is an iOS framework comes with iOS 11, helps to process models in your apps for face detection.

--

--
30- Explain JSONEncoder and JSONDecoder in Swift4

Decodable protocol, which allows us to take data and create instances of our object, populated with the data passed down from the server.

Encodable protocol to take instances of our object and turn it into data. With that data, we can store it to the files, send it to the server, whatever you need to do with it.

--
What is CocoaTouch ?

CocoaTouch is a library used to build executable applications on iOS. CocoaTouch is an abstract layer on the iOS.

--

What is NotificationCenter ?

NotificationCenter is an observer pattern, The NSNotificationCenter singleton allows us to broadcast information using an object called NSNotification.

The biggest difference between KVO and NotificationCenter is that KVOtracks specific changes to an object, while NotificationCenter is used to track generic events.

--

Explain Sequence in Swift

Sequence is a basic type in Swift for defining an aggregation of elements that distribute sequentially in a row. All collection types inherit from Sequence such as Array, Set, Dictionary.

--

What kind of benefits does Xcode server have for developers?

Xcode server will automatically check out our project, build the app, run tests, and archive the app for distribution.
--
What is Xcode Bot?

Xcode Server uses bots to automatically build your projects. A bot represents a single remote repository, project, and scheme. We can also control the build configuration the bot uses and choose which devices and simulators the bot will use.
--
Explain .gitignore

.gitignore is a file extension that you tell Git server about document types, and folders that you do not want to add to the project or do not want to track changes made in Git server projects.

--

What is an “app ID” and a “bundle ID” ?

A bundle ID is the identifier of a single app. For example, if your organization’s domain is xxx.com and you create an app named Facebook, you could assign the string com.xxx.facebook as our app’s bundle ID.

An App ID is a two-part string used to identify one or more apps from a single development team. You need Apple Developer account for an App ID.

--

What is CoreSpotlight?

CoreSpotlight allows us to index any content inside of our app. While NSUserActivity is useful for saving the user’s history, with this API, you can index any data you like. It provides access to the CoreSpotlight index on the user’s device.
--

What are layer objects?

Layer objects are data objects which represent visual content and are used by views to render their content. Custom layer objects can also be added to the interface to implement complex animations and other types of sophisticated visual effects.
--
Explain AVFoundation framework

We can create, play audio and visual media. AVFoundation allows us to work on a detailed level with time-based audio-visual data. With it, we can create, edit, analyze, and re-encode media files. AVFoundation has two sets of API, one that’s video, and one that is audio.
--
Explain Property Observer

A property observer observes and responds to changes in a property’s value. With property observer, we don’t need to reset the controls, every time attributes change.

--
What’s the difference between a xib and a storyboard?

Both are used in Xcode to layout screens (view controllers). A xib defines a single View or View Controller screen, while a storyboard shows many view controllers and also shows the relationship between them.
--
Explain how to add frameworks in Xcode project?

First, choose the project file from the project navigator on the left side of the project window
Then choose the target where you want to add frameworks in the project settings editor
Choose the “Build Phases” tab, and select “Link Binary With Libraries” to view all of the frameworks
To add frameworks click on “+” sign below the list select framework and click on add button.

------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------------
Realm is a cross platform mobile database for iOS (available in Swift & Objective-C) and Android. Realm is built to be better and faster than SQLite and Core Data.

Observer Pattern
Facade Design Pattern

SBJson framework is supported by iOS. It is a JSON parser and generator for Objective-C 

HTTP Live Streaming (HLS) technology from Apple


Name the framework that is used to construct application’s user interface for iOS
The UIKit framework is used to develop application’s user interface. The UIKit framework provides event handling, drawing model, windows, views, and controls, specifically designed for a touch screen interface.

How can you respond to state transitions on your app?
State transitions can be responded to state changes in an appropriate way by calling corresponding methods on app’s delegate object.

What is the difference between retain & assign?
  Assign creates a reference from one object to another without increasing the source’s retain count.
  Retain creates a reference from one object to another and increases the retain count of the source object.


Here are a few common ways to specify the layout of elements in UIView:
• Using InterfaceBuilder, you can add an XIB file to your project, layout elements within it, and then load the XIB in your application code (either automatically, based on naming conventions, or manually). Also, using InterfaceBuilder you can create a storyboard for your application.
• You can write your own code to use NSLayoutConstraints and have elements in a view arranged by Auto Layout.
• You can create CGRects describing the exact coordinates for each element and pass them to UIView’s – (id)initWithFrame:(CGRect)frame method.


9. What is the difference between atomic and non-atomic properties? Which is the default for synthesized properties? When would you use one over the other?
Properties specified as atomic are guaranteed to always return a fully initialized object. This also happens to be the default state for synthesized properties.
While it’s a good practice to specify atomic to remove the potential for confusion, if you leave it off, your properties will still be atomic.
This guarantee of atomic properties comes at the cost of performance.
However, if you have a property for which you know that retrieving an uninitialized value is not a risk (e.g. if all access to the property is already synchronized via other means), setting it to non-atomic can boost performance.

Explain Singleton class.

Only one instance of that class is created in the application.


Does Objective-C contain private methods?
NO, there is nothing called a private method in Object-C programming. If a method is defined in .m only then it becomes protected. If in .h,it is public.
If you really want a private method then you need to add a local category/ unnamed category/ class extension in the class and add the method in the category and define it in the class.m.

 What is plist?
Plist refers to Property lists that organize data into named values and lists of values using several object types.
The user defaults system, which you programmatically access through the NSUserDefaults class, uses property lists to store objects representing user preferences. 

What is the purpose of reuseIdentifier? What is the benefit of setting it to a non-nil value?
The reuseIdentifier is used to group together similar rows in a UITableView; i.e., rows that differ only in their content, but otherwise have similar layouts.
A UITableView will normally allocate just enough UITableViewCell objects to display the content visible in the table.
 If reuseIdentifier is set to a non-nil value then UITableView will first attempt to reuse an already allocated UITableViewCell with the same reuseIdentifier when the table view is scrolled.
 If reuseIdentifier has not been set, the UITableView will be forced to allocate new UITableViewCell objects for each new item that scrolls into view, potentially leading to laggy animations.

What is the difference between an “app ID” and a “bundle ID” and what is each used for?
An App ID is a two-part string to identify one or more apps from a single development team. The string consists of a Team ID and a bundle ID search string, with a period (.) separating the two parts.
The Team ID is supplied by Apple and is unique to a specific development team while a bundle ID search string is supplied by the developer to match either the bundle ID of a single app or a set of bundle IDs for a group of apps.
Since most users consider the App ID as a string, they think it is interchangeable with Bundle ID. Once the App ID is created in the Member Center, you can only use the App ID Prefix that matches the Bundle ID of the Application Bundle.
The bundle ID uniquely defines each App. It is specified in Xcode. A single Xcode project can have multiple targets and therefore, output multiple apps. A common use case for this – An app having both lite/free and pro/full versions or branded multiple ways.


 What is Abstract class in Cocoa?
Cocoa doesn’t provide anything called abstract. We can create a class abstract that gets checked only at runtime while it is not checked at compile time.

@interface AbstractClass : NSObject
@end
@implementation AbstractClass
+ (id)alloc{
    if (self == [AbstractClass class]) {
        NSLog(@"Abstract Class can’t be used");
    }
    return [super alloc];
@end


What is NSURLConnection class? Define its types and use case.
There are two ways of using NSURLConnection class. One is asynchronous and the other is synchronous.
An asynchronous connection will create a new thread and performs its download process on the new thread. A synchronous connection will block the calling thread while downloading content and doing its communication.
Many developers think that a synchronous connection blocks the main thread, which is not true. A synchronous connection will always block the thread from which it is fired. If you fire a synchronous connection from the main thread, the main thread will be blocked. But, if you fire a synchronous connection from a thread other than the main thread, it will be like an asynchronous connection and won’t block your main thread.
In fact, the only difference between a synchronous and an asynchronous connection is that at runtime, a thread will be created for the asynchronous connection while it won’t do the same for a synchronous connection.
In order to create an asynchronous connection, we need to do the following:
1. Have our URL in an instance of NSString
2. Convert our string to an instance of NSURL
3. Place our URL in an URL Request of type NSURLRequest, or in the case of mutable URLs, in an instance of NSMutableURLRequest.
4. Create an instance of NSURLConnection and pass the URL request to it.

Learn more about iOS, in this iOS online training course.

What is the difference between Array vs NSArray ?

Array can only hold one type of data, NSArray can hold different types of data. The array is value type, NSArray is immutable reference type.

 What is NSLayoutAnchor ?

With iOS 9, Apple introduced the NSLayoutAnchor class to make writing autolayout easier with code.

There are three subclasses of NSLayoutAnchor:

NSLayoutXAxisAnchor This subclass is used to create horizontal constraints
NSLayoutYAxisAnchor This subclass is used to create vertical constraints
NSLayoutDimension This subclass is used to create the width and height constraints

What is themutating keyword ?

The mutating keyword is used to let variables be modified in a struct or enum.

27- What is snapshot testing ?

Snapshot testing is a way to automatically test the aesthetic part of your UI. It consists of creating a view from your app and comparing it against a reference image.

28- What is circular dependencies ?

A circular dependency is a relation between two or more modules which either directly or indirectly depend on each other to function properly. Such modules are also known as mutually recursive.


29- What’s the difference between MKAnnotation and MKPointAnnotation?

MKAnnotation is a protocol. Typically, we will create a NSObject subclass that implements this protocol. Instances of this custom class will then serve as your map annotation.

MKPointAnnotation is a class that implements MKAnnotation. We can use it directly if we want our own business logic on the annotation.


 Explain Main Thread Checker

The Main Thread Checker is a new tool launched with Xcode 9 which detects the invalid use of Apple’s frameworks like UIKit, AppKit etc that supposed to be used from main thread but accidentally used in the background thread. The effect of the invalid usage can result in missed UI updates, visual defects, data corruption, and crashes. You can read more about the Main Thread Checker here.


What is the difference Stack and Heap ?

Our code takes up some space in the iOS. The size of this is sometimes fixed and sometimes it can change according to what the user will enter during the program. Basically we have two different methods because of this difference: Stack and Heap

Stack is used and automatically removes itself from memory after work is finished. But in Heap the user could do it by writing manual code for deleting from memory.

Stack;

Stack is easy to use.
It’s kept in RAM on the computer.
Created variables are automatically deleted when they exit the stack.
It is quite fast compared to Heap.
Constructed variables can be used without a pointer.
Heap;

Compared to Stack, it is quite slow.
It creates memory problems if not used correctly.
Variables are used with pointers.
It is created at runtime.


Explain Encoding, Decoding and Serialization, Deserialization

Serialization is the process of converting data into a single string or json so it can be stored or transmitted easily. Serialization, also known as encoding. The reverse process of turning a single string into a data is called decoding, or deserialization. In swift we useCodable protocol that a type can conform to, to declare that it can be encoded and decoded. It’s basically an alias for the Encodable and Decodable protocols.


What is the purpose of using IBAction and IBOutlet ?

IBAction and IBOutlet are macros defined to denote variables and methods that can be referred to in Interface Builder.

IBAction resolves to void and IBOutlet resolves to nothing, but they signify to Xcode and Interface builder that these variables and methods can be used in Interface builder to link UI elements to your code.

Explain the difference between Generics and AnyObject in Swift

Generics are type safe, meaning if you pass a string as a generic and try to use as a integer the compiler will complain and you will not be able to compile your. Because Swift is using Static typing, and is able to give you a compiler error.

What is Smoke Testing?

Smoke Testing, also known as “Build Verification Testing”, is a type of software testing that comprises of a non-exhaustive set of tests that aim at ensuring that the most important functions work.

The term ‘smoke testing’, it is said, came to software testing from a similar type of hardware testing, in which the device passed the test if it did not catch fire (or smoked) the first time it was turned on.

What is the meaning of id ?

id is a pointer to any type, it always points to an Objective-C object. The AnyObject protocol is similar and it helps bridge the gap between Swift and Objective-C.







